{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "In voice communication, what term is pronounced three times in a distress call?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "PAN PAN",
        "b": "SECURITE",
        "c": "MAYDAY",
        "d": "SOS"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "\"PAN PAN\" is pronounced three times in voice communication to indicate an urgency signal and message, not a distress call.",
        "b": "\"SECURITE\" is pronounced in voice communication to indicate a safety signal and message, not a distress call. ",
        "c": "In voice communication, a distress call is pronounced as \"MAYDAY,\" repeated three times.",
        "d": "\"SOS\" is not typically pronounced three times in voice communication for a distress call."
      },
      "correctAnswer": "C",
      "difficulty": "Beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "In practical terms, what does the Q code QSV signify during communication?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Distress signal",
        "b": "Urgency signal",
        "c": "Safety signal",
        "d": "Test signal"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Q codes related to distress signals often include the term \"MAYDAY\" (e.g., QRT MAYDAY). QSV is not associated with distress signals.",
        "b": "Q codes related to urgency signals may involve terms like \"PAN PAN\" (e.g., QRX PAN PAN). QSV is specifically associated with test signals, not urgency signals.",
        "c": "Q codes related to safety signals might include terms like \"SECURITE\" (e.g., QRK SECURITE). QSV is specifically associated with test signals, not safety signals.",
        "d": "The Q code QSV signifies a test signal, which is used for the adjustment of transmitters or receivers during practical communication."
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "Beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the callsign used in the simulation?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "VU8ZXS",
        "b": "VU2ABC",
        "c": "VU9VNC",
        "d": "VX2ABC"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "This callsign is not mentioned as the designated callsign in the simulation.",
        "b": "Callsigns serve as unique identifiers for stations, and in this scenario, VU2ABC is the designated callsign being used.",
        "c": "This callsign is not mentioned as the designated callsign in the simulation.",
        "d": "This callsign is not mentioned as the designated callsign in the simulation."
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "Beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "what is the Morse Code representation for a distress call?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "PAN PAN",
        "b": "VVV",
        "c": "SOS",
        "d": "XXX"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "\"PAN PAN\" is not a Morse Code representation. It is a term used in voice communication to indicate an urgency signal.",
        "b": "\"VVV\" is not a Morse Code representation for a distress call. It is associated with test signals in Morse Code.",
        "c": "The Morse Code representation for a distress call in maritime communication is the iconic SOS.",
        "d": "\"XXX\" is not a Morse Code representation for a distress call. It does not have a specific meaning in Morse Code related to distress signaling."
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "Beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "What term is pronounced in voice communication when issuing a safety signal ?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "PAN PAN",
        "b": "SECURITE",
        "c": "MAYDAY",
        "d": "VVV"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "\"PAN PAN\" is pronounced in voice communication to indicate an urgency signal.",
        "b": "In voice communication, the term \"SECURITE\" is pronounced when issuing a safety signal.",
        "c": "\"MAYDAY\" is pronounced in voice communication to indicate a distress call. ",
        "d": "\"VVV\" is associated with test signals in voice communication. It is not used for safety, urgency, or distress signaling."
      },
      "correctAnswer": "",
      "difficulty": "Beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of distress emergency is indicated when there is a fire onboard a vessel and immediate action is required to control and extinguish the fire?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Flooding emergency",
        "b": "Man overboard emergency",
        "c": "Abandoning ship emergency",
        "d": "Fire emergency"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "A flooding emergency is declared when there is a significant ingress of water into a vessel, and immediate action is required to control and mitigate the flooding.",
        "b": "A man overboard emergency is declared when a person falls overboard, and immediate action is taken to rescue and recover the individual from the water.",
        "c": "An abandoning ship emergency is declared when the vessel is in imminent danger.",
        "d": "A fire emergency is indicated when there is a fire onboard a vessel, requiring immediate action to control and extinguish the fire."
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "Intermediate"
    },
    {
      "question": "What distress emergency involves a threat to the safety of individuals onboard due to a sudden medical issue or injury?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Fire emergency",
        "b": "Man overboard emergency",
        "c": "Medical emergency",
        "d": "Flooding emergency"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "A fire emergency is declared when there is a fire onboard, and immediate action is required to control and extinguish the fire.",
        "b": "A man overboard emergency is declared when a person falls overboard, and immediate action is taken to rescue and recover the individual from the water.",
        "c": "A medical emergency involves a threat to the safety of individuals onboard due to a sudden medical issue or injury.",
        "d": "A flooding emergency is declared when there is a significant ingress of water into a vessel, and immediate action is required to control and mitigate the flooding."
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "Intermediate"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of safety emergency is declared when there is a need to issue weather warnings to nearby vessels or aircraft?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Medical safety emergency",
        "b": "Weather safety emergency",
        "c": "Fire safety emergency",
        "d": "Collision avoidance safety emergency"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "A medical safety emergency is declared when there is a threat to the safety of individuals onboard due to a sudden medical issue or injury.",
        "b": "A weather safety emergency is declared to issue weather warnings and ensure the safety of nearby vessels or aircraft.",
        "c": "A fire safety emergency is declared when there is a fire onboard, and immediate action is required to control and extinguish the fire.",
        "d": "Collision avoidance safety emergency is not a standard term."
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "Intermediate"
    },
    {
      "question": "what type of safety emergency involves the communication of urgent messages related to power outage?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Navigation safety emergency",
        "b": "Power outage safety emergency",
        "c": "Medical safety emergency",
        "d": "Weather safety emergency"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "A navigation safety emergency typically involves urgent messages related to navigational hazards, course corrections, or other safety-related concerns during navigation.",
        "b": "A power outage safety emergency involves the communication of urgent messages related to a sudden loss of power onboard and the need for immediate safety measures. ",
        "c": "A medical safety emergency involves urgent messages related to a sudden medical issue or injury onboard, requiring immediate attention and potential medical assistance.",
        "d": "A weather safety emergency is declared to issue weather warnings and ensure the safety of nearby vessels or aircraft due to adverse weather conditions."
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "Intermediate"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the Morse code representation for a distress signal used in maritime communication?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "- - -",
        "b": "...---...",
        "c": " ...- ...-",
        "d": "-..-..-.."
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "The Morse code representation \"- - -\" does not correspond to a distress signal. ",
        "b": "The Morse code representation for a distress signal in maritime communication is \"...---...\"",
        "c": "The Morse code representation \"...- ...-\" also does not correspond to a distress signal. ",
        "d": "The Morse code representation \"-..-..-..\" does not correspond to a distress signal."
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "Advanced"
    },
    {
      "question": "In Morse Code, what sequence represents an urgency signal used in voice communication during maritime distress situations?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "-..--..--..-",
        "b": "- - -",
        "c": "-..-..-..",
        "d": " - - "
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "In Morse Code, the sequence \"-..--..--..-\" represents an urgency signal in voice communication during maritime distress situations.",
        "b": "The Morse code representation \"- - -\" corresponds to the letter \"O\" and is not specifically used as an urgency signal.",
        "c": "The Morse code representation \"-..-..-..\" does not correspond to an urgency signal.",
        "d": "The Morse code representation \"- -\" corresponds to the letter \"T\" and is not specifically used as an urgency signal "
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "Advanced"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the Morse code representation for a safety signal used in aviation communication?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "...",
        "b": ".--",
        "c": "-..",
        "d": "---"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "The Morse code representation \"...\" corresponds to the letter \"S\" and is not specifically used as a safety signal in aviation communication.",
        "b": "The Morse code representation \".--\" corresponds to the letter \"W\" and is not specifically used as a safety signal in aviation communication.",
        "c": "The Morse code representation \"-..\" corresponds to the letter \"D\" and is not specifically used as a safety signal in aviation communication.",
        "d": "The Morse code representation for a safety signal in aviation communication is \"---\"."
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "Advanced"
    },
    {
      "question": "In Morse Code, what sequence represents a Test signal used in maritime communication?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "-..-..-..",
        "b": "...-",
        "c": "-.-.-",
        "d": "...- ...- ...-"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "The Morse code representation \"-..-..-..\" does not correspond to a Test signal.",
        "b": "The Morse code representation \"...-\" corresponds to the letter \"V\" and is not specifically used as a Test signal in maritime communication.",
        "c": "The Morse code representation \"-.-.-\" is used as the Morse Code representation for the letter \"C\" and is not specifically used as a Test signal in maritime communication.",
        "d": " In Morse Code, the sequence \"...- ...- ...-\" represents a Test signal used in maritime communication."
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "Advanced"
    }
    
  ]
}
